<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-02T16:58:45+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Beck Chamberlain Portfolio</title><entry><title type="html">My Projects</title><link href="/projects" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Projects" /><published>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects"><![CDATA[<h3 id="morse-code-translator">Morse Code Translator</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/BeckCham/morselike_code_translator">View on GitHub</a></p>

<h3 id="card-game-simulator">Card Game Simulator</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/BeckCham/card_game_simulator">View on GitHub</a></p>

<h3 id="fish-feeder">Fish Feeder</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/BeckCham/fish_feeder">View on GitHub</a></p>

<h3 id="rhyme-finder">Rhyme Finder</h3>
<p><a href="https://github.com/BeckCham/rhyme_checker">View on GitHub</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Morse Code Translator View on GitHub]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life AFK</title><link href="/life-afk" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life AFK" /><published>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/life-afk</id><content type="html" xml:base="/life-afk"><![CDATA[<h3 id="sea-rowing-competition">Sea Rowing Competition</h3>
<h4 id="may-2025">May 2025</h4>
<p><img src="/assets/img/SeaRowing.jpeg" alt="Sea Rowing Photo" /></p>

<p>I was one of the committee members who restarted Aberystwyth University rowing club last September, and I’ve adored the experience of building the club from the ground up. We had the chance to take part in a league race for the first time this May, so we put together a team to see how our progress stood up.
The team was made up of 5 people, with me in the stroke and a member of the town club coxing. Our group ended up coming in first place, which was not only a personal victory but one for the club as well.</p>

<h3 id="ada-lovelace-colloquium">Ada Lovelace Colloquium</h3>
<h4 id="april-2025">April 2025</h4>
<p><img src="/assets/img/Lovelace.jpeg" alt="Ada Lovelace Photo" /></p>

<p>I had the opportunity to present a poster at the BSC Ada Lovelace Colloquium in Glasgow. I decided to create a poster about how AI is being used to manipulate people and how it can and will be used as a form of psychological warfare in the future if we do not introduce proper regulation. This is a topic which is important in an age where technology is changing faster than we can keep up with it, and hostile groups are grooming people online more than ever</p>

<p>Whilst I enjoyed the experience of researching a topic, then creating a poster and presenting my ideas, what I benefited from the most was meeting and interacting with my peers. It was inspiring to see such a diverse selection of ideas and presentations, and it encouraged me to push myself further with my submission next year. I hugely enjoyed listening to professionals in the field and hearing about their experiences, and I hope to attend the event again next year.</p>

<h3 id="endeavour-workshops">Endeavour Workshops</h3>
<h4 id="summer-2019--2020">Summer 2019 &amp; 2020</h4>

<p>I planned, led, and executed two workshops in partnership schemes connected to King Edward VI School. This scheme aims to provide primary school children with new experiences, broadening their horizons and enabling them to explore their interests. Both times I volunteered to help with this program, I was chosen to lead the planning and organisation of the activities. This all took place over the course of two days. On the first day, three other volunteers and I designed activities that would make up a 45-minute class. On the second day, we ran the workshop three times for a class of 30 children.</p>

<h4 id="debating-and-public-speaking-workshop-2019">Debating and Public Speaking Workshop 2019</h4>

<p>My team and I decided to focus on what we thought was absolutely necessary for all forms of debating and public speaking, instead of focusing on any particular type
of debate with rigid rules. The activities we ran were: A ‘Hot-Air Balloon Debate’, we explained how this debating exercise worked, then gave them simple prompts such as what the best sport is; A fallacies lesson, where we explained what a fallicy is and the most common ones; A ‘flip flop’ game, where a student would start speaking about their opinion on a subject such as ‘superman is good’ then would need to change their opinion once the word ‘flip’ or ‘flop’ is said; Finally an speaking exercise where we taught them about key elements of public speaking such as pausing, keeping good speaking pace, looking at your audiance, and projecting your voice.</p>

<p>This workshop was hugely successful. We had 2/3 of the groups that took part in the day vote this experience as their favourite, and at the end of the session, when we asked questions to check what the students retained, every group was able to recall key details correctly.</p>

<h4 id="computer-science-workshop-2021">Computer Science Workshop 2021</h4>

<p>I was selected to lead a less experienced team, which required me to design the workshop not only with the children in mind but also with consideration for what my peers felt confident delivering. Our aim was to introduce fundamental computer science concepts, so we selected activities that were both accessible and engaging. These included demonstrating logic gates using Raspberry Pi Picos with buttons and LEDs, explaining how computers “think” through interactive examples, teaching core programming constructs using LightBot, and presenting object-oriented programming in a simple, intuitive way using Pokémon as examples.</p>

<p>The workshop was highly successful. Student feedback indicated that they enjoyed the sessions, and a clear improvement in their understanding of algorithmic problem-solving and core concepts was evident by the end of the day. We also faced the additional challenge of working with an SEN group; however, by adapting our activities, increasing engagement, and actively listening to individual needs, we were able to accommodate this effectively and ensure a positive experience for everyone.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sea Rowing Competition May 2025]]></summary></entry></feed>